（空气哇声）
-[旁白]斯坦福大学。
-[讲师]好的，第五课。
斯坦福CS193P 2020年春季。
今天我们将从一个小样开始
记忆中的访问控制。
您已经了解了访问控制
在阅读作业中
我们实际上使用了访问控制
在“记住”中，但是现在该应用访问控制了
记住并继续使用
而你应该使用它
在您所有的SwiftUI编程中永无止境。
演示之后，我们要回来
再谈一下ViewBuilder。
非常重要，非常简单的小概念
我在上一讲中已经提到过几次
但现在我们只想清楚地阐明
ViewBuilder的全部用途。
然后我们将讨论当天的主要话题，
这是形状。
如果我想绘制视图怎么办
而不是从其他视图中删除我的视图？
我怎么做？
我们将在“记忆”中进行演示，在其中添加形状
表情符号后面的那个小馅饼
您在第一堂课中看到的
然后我们进入动画主题
我们将意识到动画非常重要
在移动应用程序中，而且在Swift中超级简单
在某些方面几乎是免费的，
但是当我们开始谈论动画时
我们将迅速到达这一点
在这里我们需要谈论另一个概念
称为ViewModifiers。
ViewModifiers是基础
我们如何构建这些视图
而且您到处都在使用ViewModifiers
甚至可能根本没有意识到您正在这样做
我们将深入了解正在发生的事情
在您编写的所有SwiftUI代码中。
顺便说一句，本周不需要遵循
通过作业。
实际上，这周的功课
甚至不会被记住。
是时候编写您自己的应用程序了
从头开始。
但是我现在要做的访问控制功能
是你必须申请的东西
您的所有代码。
所以跟着记住
可能是一个很好的学习经验。
在本季度末，我们很有可能会回来
记住做功课
您尚未完成记忆。
在那种情况下，我会尽力做到这一点
这样我本周要向您展示的代码
将来的作业中不必包括
记住。
我不能百分百地承诺，
但我希望情况确实如此。
话虽如此，很多学生发现
跟随或真正帮助他们学习，
所以我想我实际上建议您这样做。
因此，让我们从潜水开始
将整个访问控制更改为“记住”。
现在，我们已经在记忆中使用过一次作为控件
只有一次，就在这里，私人的。
访问控制就是控制访问
不同的结构必须具有彼此的变量。
通过使该模型完全私有
在我们的ViewModel中，
我们已经迫使ViewModel制作这种无功卡
以便视图可以获取卡片，
当然我们要有这个意图
这样，如果有人想更改模型，
他们必须表达自己的意图，如何做到这一点
很好，这使它变得私有。
但是，我们可以更进一步。
在我们的模型中，卡片本身
可能想成为私人的。
这是为什么？
好吧，我们不要任何人进来
并把这些卡片弄糟。
设置为isMatched
甚至将它们正面朝上或朝下放置。
卡是否匹配完全在权限范围内
此MemoryGame模型。
只有它知道卡是否应该匹配
所有逻辑都在选择卡中。
因此，我们真的想将此私有化。
但是将其私有化实际上将是一个问题。
如果我们回到这里，看看这行代码
并与那里的那个人一起编译它，
您可以看到我们收到错误消息。
提示无法访问卡
由于私人保护水平。
实际上，这些卡现在是私人的
因此不再允许使用ViewModel
访问此变量。
但是ViewModel确实需要访问
至少要阅读卡片。
我们还要如何在用户界面中显示卡片？
因此，我们不能真正将其私有化，
但是我们可以使用不同的访问控制级别
设置好了。
私有集意味着将其设置为私有，
但不是。
这正是我们在这种情况下想要的。
我们希望人们能够看一下我们的卡片
因此他们可以将它们放在用户界面中，进行显示。
但是，在更换卡片时，
我们绝对希望为我们自己保留。
因此，私有集是要设置的真正的通用访问控制。
现在，访问控制不仅仅是我们在var上设置的功能。
这也是我们可以在功能上设置的
和我们自己的内部计算机变量。
例如，indexOfTheOneAndOnlyFaceUpCard
在我们的模型中，这纯粹是私人的事情。
这是我们要弄清楚怎么做的私人逻辑
我们的配对游戏。
这绝对是要私密的。
我们当然不希望任何人设置此设置，
可能完全把我们搞砸了
我们真的不希望有人看着它
因为如果他们开始看它
他们可能会依赖它
然后我必须始终使用这种特殊策略
按照我可能不想做的逻辑，
所以这就是我们要保持此私密性的原因。
当然选择不能是私有的。
这是人们玩我们的游戏的方式
而且我们的init不想成为私有的。
允许您使用私有初始化。
这是一种罕见的情况，
但是你可以让init只在你的结构内部使用
创建也许将要使用的私有实例。
现在struct Card在这里很有意思。
您可能在想，哦，私人场景，私人场景，
私有集，私有集。
我们不希望任何人设置这些。
但是，获取卡的唯一途径
模型之外的对象就是通过此数组。
并且此数组已经是私有集。
这是一个值类型。
实际的卡在此阵列中。
当有人打电话给这个变种来获得这个，
他们正在获取副本，并且该副本是只读的
因为私人订位。
因此，由于任何人都无法获得可写卡，
对我们来说，以这种方式离开这些变量非常好。
好吧，那回到我们的ViewModel呢？
清楚地访问模型。
这不必是私有的。
无论如何它都是只读的，因为它是只读的var。
绝对意图是非私有的。
人们还会如何表达自己的意图？
但是这个createMemoryGame，这个静态函数
那可能想成为私人的。
我们可能不想要其他人，
特别是我们的View，以创建一个MemoryGame。
创建一个MemoryGame，创建我们的模型，
那是我们要做的。
在家庭作业中，您必须具有新的游戏功能。
您可能会在这里创建一个新的MemoryGame，
但这将必须在您的ViewModel中发生
因为例如Views绝不可能
可以负责创建模型。
因此，ViewModel确实希望这是私有函数。
我们认为呢？
所以这是我们对这里的看法。
现在让我们看一下CardView。
这很有趣。
这些绘图常数在这里。
这些绝对可以是私人的。
真的没有任何人会的理由，他们是
还是可以，但是没有理由有人
想要在这里访问这些东西，
因此这绝对可以是私人的。
此var主体必须是非私有的
因为系统将调用该名称。
就是这样，它如何为我们的视图赋予主体
它会在需要的任何时间打电话
了解如何绘制此CardView。
但是这个小助手功能
我们从GeometryReader内部调用的
没有理由公开，好吗？
只有我们从自己的代码中调用它
在CardView内部。
那这个变种呢？
这可以是私人的吗？
不，因为当我们创建CardView时，
我们需要给这个东西一个初始值，
因此我们必须能够在此处访问它。
如果我们将此设为私人，
那么我们将无法在创建它时对其进行设置
这将是未初始化的
而这在Swift中是不允许的。
那这里呢？
好吧，同样，var body必须公开
而且这里的ViewModel必须是公开的
因为例如当我们创建预览器时，
我们正在指定ViewModel，
在我们的小SceneDelegate中，
当我们创建应用程序窗口的主视图时，
我们在这里表达它。
同样，这必须是公开的。
在Grid中呢？
因此在Grid中，这是一个有趣的案例。
这些var必须公开吗？
嗯，不是因为我们有这个公共初始化程序
设置这些变量。
因此我们可以将这些完全设为私人
那会很好。
这些var只需要公开
如果您要让人们直接初始化它们。
但是由于我们有一个初始化器来初始化它们，
他们不需要公开。
可能希望它们是私有的。
当然，Var主体必须是公开的。
但是，这些小小的身体助手功能，
他们不需要公开。
在GridLayout中如何？
因此，我们有了GridLayout。
当然我们需要构造函数
或将初始化程序公开
我们需要itemSize和位置公开，
否则，人们将如何使用它？
但是这些变量对于使这些私有集非常重要。
为什么将这三个变量设为私有集如此重要？
计算这三个变量
从初始化程序，
初始化程序中通过的值在这里。
如果我们不将这些私人套装，
有人可能会认为他们可以重置此大小变量
并且这些将自动重置。
但这不是事实。
初始化GridLayout后，它将永久修复。
所以我们希望人们知道
他们只能从此处读取这些值。
您无法设置此项，并期望它们会发生变化
或类似的东西。
这就是访问控制的情况
实际上可以帮助人们了解如何使用此东西。
好吧，显然是我们的firstIndex，我们想要那个公众。
我们将其添加到所有数组中。
与我们的var相同。
我们正在公开场合。
就是这样了。
这就是我们在Memorize中设置访问控制的方式。
每次我们添加新功能时，
当您在家庭作业中这样做时，
你绝对应该把私人
无论什么地方都应该是私人的。
现在你们中的许多人已经在做家庭作业。
您尚未执行此操作，我鼓励您继续执行此操作。
我们不会让您对此负责
在第二个作业中
但是我们肯定会在第三项任务中。
让我们运行我们的应用程序
并确保将所有这些私有工作
它做到了。
有时您会运行您的应用程序，并且会意识到，
哦，我将其设为私有，但实际上这是必需的。
然后你必须决定，
真的要我们访问吗？
如果是这样，是私有集还是私有集？
这就是我们很少进行访问控制的过程。
让我们回到幻灯片
并详细讨论ViewBuilder。
因此，ViewBuilder基于通用技术
最近添加到了Swift
支持面向列表的语法。
有很多东西被表达为列表，
例如HTML，它只是一个列表。
一段然后是一个嵌入的东西
然后是另一个段落，标题或其他内容，
它们只是在页面上列出。
所以在Swift中会很好
能够代表这些
某些面向列表的本地语法。
一旦有了这种机制，您就会迅速意识到，
哦，有很多地方
我们只需要一个View列表，
就像我们卡的正面一样。
我们只想列出两个RoundedRectangles
还有表情符号
因此，ViewBuilder让开发人员可以做到这一点
@ViewBuilder是关键字。
再次，它不是语言的一部分。
@ViewBuilder就像@Published
或@ObservedObject，
这是基于其他技术的东西。
但是@ViewBuilder，可以标记此关键字
到返回某些View的任何函数上。
所以只要函数返回一些View
您可以使用@ViewBuilder标记该功能
现在编译器将解释
该函数的花括号中包含什么
成为视图列表，而不仅仅是任意代码，
视图列表。
这就是ViewBuilder的工作方式。
现在，您要标记的功能
使用@ViewBuilder，
它返回一些视图，它是单个视图。
所以ViewBuilder，这就是为什么它被称为ViewBuilder，
它将视图列表构建为一个视图。
结合起来的那个观点
很多时候将是一个TupleView。
因此，如果其中有2到10个视图，
这将是一个TupleView。
TupleView最多有10个无关项，
其中有10个视图。
并注意它仅限于10。
因此，如果您开始拥有11个以上的视图，
您将不得不将其分成几组，
TupleViews的TupleViews可在其中获得那么多视图。
很难想象拥有超过10个视图
刚连续列出。
你几乎肯定会把它分解
带有CardViews之类的子视图，
EmojiGameView等的子视图。
因此，实际上并没有太大的限制，但确实存在。
另一种观点可能是
作为ConditionalContent视图，
下栏的ConditionalContent视图，
这就是视图创建的
当那里有if-else时。
请记住，ViewBuilder中的if-elses
只是选择要包含在列表中的视图，
就像是CardViews的正面一样
或CardView的背面。
因此，将创建此ConditionalContent视图
只是有谓词可以测试isFaceUp
然后有两个视图
可能是TupleView或其他视图
它会从中选择。
甚至可以是允许的EmptyView。
我不知道你为什么一定要那样
但你可以拥有它。
但是要记住的最重要的一点是
可以是这些东西的任何组合。
所以你可以有一个TupleView
或TupleView中的其中一项是条件视图
在该条件视图中
还有另一个TupleView等。
这样您就可以构建这种任意复杂的
视图的条件列表
这才是真正的目的。
现在请注意，其中一些ViewBuilder API
尚未完全公开。
就像看到条件栏下的条件，
显然前面有一个下杠
还没准备好迎接黄金时段，还没有完全公开。
我敢打赌，如果您在文档中查找
你甚至在那里都找不到任何东西，
但这没关系，因为我们实际上不在乎
这些是什么样的看法。
TupleViews，ConditionalContent等
我们所关心的只是它的某些视图，对不对？
我们只能标记一个返回一些View的函数
用这个东西。
这就是我们所关心的。
所有这些东西都是一些观点
这样对我们来说足够了。
同样，任何函数，也是只读的计算变量
也可以使用此ViewBuilder进行标记
并在上面标记它，以便功能
被解释为ViewBuilder。
这是我们的记忆样本。
假设我想排除卡片的正面，
这两个RoundedRectangles和您在此处看到的文本
变成自己的小功能。
好吧，我可以使用func，卡片正面
它返回一些视图
在这里，我通常必须将其放在一个组中
或类似的东西，
但是相反，我可以将其标记为@ViewBuilder
现在里面的花括号
将被解释为视图列表。
我可以在这里放一些东西
如果我想在这里做整个卡，我可以
并拥有if isFaceUp，
所有这些东西完全允许。
这只是带有这些if-thens的View列表
允许在那里。
此特定的绿色代码将返回TupleView
三个不在乎
是RoundedRectangle，RoundedRectangle，Text。
当然，有两个TupleViews与八个无关项
九，否则将是三。
同样，我们不在乎它在那儿执行TupleView。
绝对不在乎。
我们只关心这一些视图。
现在您也可以使用此@ViewBuilder
标记功能参数
本身就是返回某些View的函数。
例如，我们的Grid的viewForItem参数，对不对？
那是一个带物品的功能
并返回了一个视图，那将是合格的
用@ViewBuilder标记。
现在我们不在网格中执行此操作
我将在稍后讨论，为什么我们没有，
但做到这一点的人是GeometryReader
HStack，VStack和ForEach都这样做，
但让我们看看声明
GeometryReader的初始值设定项可能看起来像。
您已经有了GeometryReader，对吗？
这是无关紧要的内容，
被限制为一个视图。
因此，GeometryReader的初始化程序
我们知道需要满足，这花括号的东西，
给您GeometryProxy，
我们得到大小的东西，
它返回的内容就是一些View。
所以既然这个内容争论
是一个返回一些View的函数，
可以将其标记为@ViewBuilder
GeometryReader的功能。
它将其标记为@ViewBuilder。
这意味着您的GeometryReader里面是什么，
小花括号是“视图”列表，
将被解释为视图列表。
就这么简单。
通常取决于GeometryReader之类的东西，
Hstack，VStack，
决定您是否通过了争论
成为视图列表很有意义。
对于那些家伙，这就是他们的决定。
现在，您可能会问，为什么我们不在Grid中执行此操作？
网格要求您提供特定项目的视图
然后我们传递一个函数
我们为什么不说@ViewBuilder
在网格中查看项目参数？
那么答案与这件事有关
ViewBuilder仍然是私有的。
例如它的实现
无法提取视图
从TupleView，ConditionalContent，
只是你不能让他们离开那里。
因此，Grid不可能知道它们的全部。
在当前的@ViewBuilder中不公开。
我确定这将是公开的
最终你可以做到
然后也许有Grid的论点是有意义的，
但即使到那时Grid还是二维数组。
通常，这将是相当数量的View。
您不太可能会列出他们，
特别是如果您要拥有10个或更少
可能，但不太可能。
因此，Grid与ForEach息息相关
并以ForEach相同的方式表示
可能还不错。
就在我们离开ViewBuilder之前，
我只想重申一下。
这张幻灯片不是新内容。
标记为ViewBuilder的内容只是视图列表。
是的，里面有条件
看看您是否在列表中包含“视图”，
但是只有一个视图列表。
因此无法在其中声明var，
您不能有任意代码。
只要您拥有ViewBuilder，
这只是其中包含if-thens的Views列表
选择哪个视图。
当天的主要话题，形状。
形状是一种协议。
它继承自View，因此所有Shapes都是View。
因此，您始终可以将Shape放在ZStack或其他任何对象中
如我们所见
RoundedRectangle，我们把它扔在那里，没问题。
当然有常见的形状
像RoundedRectangle，Circle，
胶囊是一种椭圆形的东西
和那里的其他人。
现在，形状默认情况下会自行绘制
通过使用当前的前景色填充自己。
我们在卡片背面看到了这一点。
他们采用RoundedRectangle，默认情况下会填充它。
但是我们也了解到我们可以调用笔触或填充
带有更改Shape外观方式的参数。
现在我想谈谈填充和描边
以及可以传递给它的参数。
看起来，当我们完成记忆代码时，
传递给fill的参数实际上是Color
因为您会记得第二个RoundedRectangle
从后面，实际上不，
背面的矩形一直是白色。
然后，将描边的一个放在上面。
因此，我们说的那个白色填充Color.white。
这样看来，哦，填充需要一种颜色。
但实际上填充参数不是颜色
我将借此机会充实和中风
谈论Swift中的另一个功能
称为通用函数。
您已经了解通用类型
例如Array和MemoryGame，
它的CardContent无关紧要。
好吧，函数也可以不在乎。
它们也可以是通用的。
并且他们执行类似的语法。
您可以看到填充具有此无关位S，
用S型填充什么，
看到这是一种S，
并限制了它
所以它不是完整的不在乎
有点像在乎
S必须在其中实现ShapeStyle协议。
所以这个ShapeStyle协议，我们不再谈论它，
但是如果您实现此ShapeStyle协议，
那么您就可以用来填充或描画形状。
什么样的东西实现ShapeStyle？
好吧，颜色，显然我们知道
因为我们称填充为颜色，
还有ImagePaint，可以拍摄JPEG图像
并在那里铺上油漆
好像它只是该图像的画笔一样。
也有渐变，角度和线性渐变
会显示出一系列颜色或其他颜色。
所以这些东西完全不同，
颜色，渐变，图像绘制，非常不同的东西，
真正的填充并不关心它们是什么。
这就是为什么S是无关紧要的原因。
但这确实很在乎，因为它们都实现了ShapeStyle
因为如果他们没有实现ShapeStyle
那么Shape并不真正知道如何使用它们
做填充和描边。
再说一次，我主要是向你展示这个，
是的，这样您就可以知道可以填充图像
或渐变或颜色，
而且所以你应该意识到
有这些通用功能，
无关功能
作为他们某些论点的类型。
如果您想创建自己的形状该怎么办？
您不想使用RoundedRectangle，Circle，
无论如何，您想要自己的形状。
好吧，Shape协议使用了扩展
为您实现View的body var，对吗？
因为Shape继承自View，所以Shape是View。
因此，它必须实现body var。
所有视图都必须实现该主体变量。
但是Shape为您实现了这一点。
协议及其扩展
为您实现。
但是，Shape引入了新的功能
您需要实施。
在rect中称为路径。
所以rect中的此功能路径将仅返回
称为路径的东西。
现在，路径上有很多功能，
像线到，圆弧和贝塞尔曲线。
所有这些让您从本质上画画
就像您用笔绘图一样。
因此，您将建立一些路径
用这支笔绘图，然后将其返回此处。
现在，一旦您将其退回，Shape就拥有了所有需要知道的信息
去做它做的事，
它提供了可以抚摸和填充的Shape。
现在最好通过演示展示它的工作原理。
所以我们要回到记忆
并实施那个小馅饼。
如果您还记得我们的第一堂课
有那个小馅饼，它充满生气
有点倒计时
这样，如果您足够快地匹配卡片，
你有加分。
因此，我们将在我们的记忆游戏中画图。
我们还没有动画。
动画是我们的下一个主题。
我们将回到这一点。
所以今天我们只是在学习如何创建自己的形状
通过建立那个馅饼。
我已经将游戏中的视频截图了
这样我们就可以知道我们要拍摄什么。
我们正在尝试构建这个小饼图
看起来像吃豆人之类的东西
在我们的幽灵后面。
而且SwiftUI中没有内置这样的Shape，
这种吃豆人形状
所以我们必须自己构建。
但是在我们开始构建自定义形状之前，
让我们尝试一个圆圈
在这个鬼魂后面。
“因为我们知道有一个内置的Circle，
就像这里有一个RoundedRectangle内置的大对象一样。
因此，这样做非常简单。
这是我们的视图，这是我们的CardView。
就在这里，这里是，这是背景。
这是我们的表情符号所在的位置
而这个圈子只是想活下去
就在这之间
就在背景和表情符号之间
让我们来看看。
这样就行了。
也许这就是我们开始所需要的。
好吧，让我们单击。
哦，实际上到了那里。
看一看。
哦，差不多了。
现在不太正确。
距离那里的边缘太近了，
应该有一点差距，
而且这种颜色有点太橙色了
但在球场上。
现在我们可以回到这里尝试解决此问题
然后再次运行，然后再修复一些
然后再次运行并对其进行一些调整。
但这有点乏味
当然，我们有一个更好的工具，
这是我们这里的画布
我们可以恢复并看到我们的样子
看起来像...
哦，不，所有卡都朝下。
哪种才有意义，因为那是游戏开始的方式，
但这对我来说毫无用处
使所有这些卡面朝下。
我真的希望至少其中一张卡面朝上
所以我可以做这个。
我们该怎么做？
原来，这段代码在底部
我推开了
不像我说的那样可怕
通过将其推开。
这实际上只是一个静态var，其类型为
返回整个视图以预览我们的
EmojiMemoryGameView。
现在我们正在创建一个
我们给它这个ViewModel
我们刚刚创建的。
但是没有理由
我们不能只是从这里带走这个，
把它放在一个变量中，我称之为游戏，
要求该游戏选择其中一张纸牌，
如何选择游戏中的第一张牌，
这样的事情
然后在这里使用该游戏
作为我们要预览的东西。
当然要回去了
由于我们没有单行功能，
瞧，我们马上就看到面朝上的卡片
我可能会选择第三张卡
现在向我展示了第三张卡片。
所以我可以让它挑选几张卡片。
当然如果我选三张卡
然后去玩游戏并进行比赛。
但是，这非常适合我们的需求。
我们可以回到这里开始在这个圈子上工作
并尝试使其看起来更像我们打算在这里进行。
让我们开始尝试从边缘入手
一点，所以它不会粉碎到边缘。
我们知道该怎么做。
只需在此Circle周围放置一些填充物即可。
好吧，现在，这并不是我们想要的。
填充太多。
如果我们不知道怎么办，
在那儿放些填料？
是的，我对此很满意。
虽然我的幽灵有点大，
我认为我不想猛冲到那里的边缘。
所以也许我会在这里进入常量控制面板
并将其更改为0.7，
也许0.65不，70％看起来不错。
我不想这太小。
这是该卡的目的，实际上是为了证明这一点。
所以我不想在那儿过小。
那么这种真正的鲜艳橙色呢？
好吧，事实证明我们可以做一个橙色
在这里有点通透或透视
通过使其半透明。
而且View有一个很棒的修改器，不透明度
叫做零之间的两倍
这意味着完全透明
一到完全不透明。
现在我们可以进入中间，大概是70％
也许10％哦，太轻了。
30％，40％，我有点喜欢40％。
我认为这就是我在这里结束的事情。
差不多了。
您可以看到我们确实拥有我们想要的外观
除了这是一个圆形而不是我们的饼图。
做我们的吃豆人派
我们只需要在这里替换Circle
与我们自己的自定义形状。
因此，让我们创建它。
我要去File，New
因为我们在这里创建新事物。
这将是一个SwiftUI视图，因为形状是视图，
但是如果我们选择此模板，我们将获得该var body
Shape协议为我们提供了这一点。
所以我们要在这里选择Swift文件
确保我们将其放在正确的位置。
我将其命名为Pie，这是我自定义Shape的名称。
让我们来创建它。
开始了。
当然，现在Shape很大程度上是UI的事情，
所以我们要导入SwiftUI，而不是那里的Foundation。
并创建一个Shape，如此简单，构造Pie。
符合Shape协议
限制和收获
它会得到一个事实，那就是视图
它可以被充满和抚摸，各种收获，
而这里唯一真正的约束是这个功能，
在rect中称为路径
它返回我们必须创建的路径，
而这条路径将成为边缘
我们正在画的东西。
所以对我们来说，它将从中间开始，然后上升，
在这里，回到中间。
那就是我们要建立的道路。
我们将使用Path中的函数进行构建
就像在此处画一条线并在此处画一条弧。
我们将把所有这些结合起来
做这条路。
一旦完成，Shape便会处理所有其余的工作。
能够填补这一切
都会照顾我们的。
我们如何返回这个路径的东西？
我要创建一个空的，我将其命名为p Path。
那是一条空的路径，我要归还它。
在这之间，我只需要调用Path中的函数
移动，画出我想画的线。
现在传递给我们的是什么？
那就是我们应该适合我们的形状的矩形。
现在几乎所有的形状
通常使用给他们的直肠中的所有空间
是的，您猜对了，因为Shape是一个View，
直肠会给你在这里
是为其提供的空间。
提供的空间。
我们有这条路，有这条路，
我们该怎么做？
让我们从矩形的中心开始。
因此，我们将获得此矩形以进行绘制。
让我们直接到它的中心开始，
就在这里，然后我们要往上走。
因此，让我们从中间开始。
因此，获得中间位置非常容易。
我只是说p路径走到中间，
这就是路径，点移到中心。
而中心将是一个变种。
让中心相等。
为了获得中心，我将创建一个CGPoint。
现在注意所有这些绘图内容，
不仅是CGFloat，还包括CGRect，CGPoint，CGSize
我们在GeometryReader上看到的，它们都是从CG开始的。
此CG代表核心图形。
那就是底层的图形系统
所有这些都是建立在
因此，找到该矩形的中心真的很容易。
X的位置就是正中
Y是矩形midY。
就是这样了。
我们有了中心，我们已经在这里开始了，
但是我们还没有画任何东西。
我们实际上还没有画线或任何东西。
所以接下来我们要做
从中心到此处画一条线。
现在我要去做，让我的馅饼，
这个开始角度和这个结束角度，
可以是您想要的任何东西。
所以你可以把你的派变成一小块
或指向任何方向的大馅饼。
所以我需要几个变量
一个是我的出发点
一个是我的结束角度。
因此，让我们将这些var放在Shape中。
这只是一个结构。
这样他就可以让vars startAngle，
但是角度是什么类型？
好吧，您可以将其设置为CGFloat或类似的东西，
但是Swift中有一个很棒的东西叫做Angle
我会告诉你的
因此，我们将使这些起始角度和终止角度成为角度。
什么是角度？
让我们继续阅读文档中的内容。
这是struct Angle，它只是一个struct
它使您可以使用度数或弧度创建角度。
希望每个人都记得三角学课
什么是弧度，对吗？零度到360度
绕圈，
弧度为零到2π。
2πr是圆的周长。
因此，弧度在圆周围为零到2π。
并注意该角度的动画效果。
以后对我们会很好。
也可以散列，
这意味着可以将其放入字典或哈希表中。
我们不需要这样做，但是这个角度非常好
我们的小类型。
我需要以某种方式计算起始位置
在这里的顶部，这个小位置，
这样我才能从这里画一条线。
所以我要说的是
addLine到顶部的开头。
所以我需要开始。
起点也等于点，CGPoint也是如此。
让我们继续将它放在多行上
并将X放在一行上，将Y放在另一行上。
所以X位置，水平位置
是中心的X加上圆的半径，
我们将不得不弄清楚，
一次又一次，我希望你能记住
八年级或九年级的三角函数
或这些天教授三角学的时候
我想做那个起始角度的余弦，
我必须用弧度来做
因为Swift中的余弦函数会产生弧度，
我也想在CGFloat世界中做到这一点，
不是Double的。
同样，Y只是中心点Y
加上半径乘以CGFloat的正弦
startAngle点弧度。
因此，我需要半径。
我的圆半径将是多少？
好吧，我可以把它的宽度
或者我可以把它做成高度。
我真的希望它是两者中的较小者。
所以在这种情况下，我绝对不想拥有自己的半径
等于这个空间的一半
因为那样的话太大了。
所以我要选择宽度或高度中较小的一个
并将其除以二，以得出半径
而不是直径。
因此，让我们使半径等于最小值
矩形的宽度和矩形的高度
我们除以二。
所以我认为这就是我们要做的
起床到这里的顶部。
现在我们需要大步向前。
好吧，转弯。
幸运的是Path也具有起弧功能。
它称为addArc，您可以用不同的方法来做。
我要在这里选择最简单的一个
让您创建弧线
通过指定圆弧的中心，圆弧的半径，
起始角度和终止角度
以及您是否要顺时针旋转
还是逆时针，对不对？
所以我们是否要像这样逆时针走
或者我们是否要像这样顺时针旋转。
因此，让我们给这个中心。
我们知道中心就是那个中心半径。
是的，我们也知道。
起始角度？
是的，我们知道起始角度。
结束角？
是的，这就是这里的变量。
这真的很容易。
那顺时针呢？
这是一个布尔值，无论我们是否顺时针旋转，
让我们也允许人们使用我们来告诉我们。
所以我们说顺时针是一个布尔，
顺时针放在这里。
而且，我们不要让他们这么说。
我们将使用默认值，我们将使用顺时针false。
那恰好是我们想要的方式，对吗？
逆时针旋转，所以我们将顺时针旋转为false
为我们的派工作。
但这只是默认设置，我们不得不选择其中之一，
我们不妨选择这个。
那是弧线。
我们在这里的小路径几乎完成了。
它绕了过去，现在需要回到中间。
所以我们需要一条线回到那里的中心。
这就是p点addLine到中心。
就是这样。
我们在这里完成了自定义形状。
我们要做的就是定义此Path并返回它，
我们有一个自定义的形状
形状会照顾其他一切，
填满它，抚摸它，所有这些东西
它知道该怎么做。
让我们回到我们的观点
在这里使用Circle的地方
我们将改用Pie。
所以，让我们做派。
糟糕，抱歉，在那里退出Xcode。
让我们回到这里。
对于那个很抱歉。
我们知道Pie有一些变种。
我要初始化起始角度和终止角度。
请注意，顺时针方向是可选的。
我们不必指定。
因此，我们选择在此处进行起始和终止角度。
现在我们要从什么角度开始？
好吧，我们想从这里开始
然后逆时针转到此处。
所以直线向上可能是角度点度为零，
然后是结束角，我们在哪里结束？
我们在这里结束。
好吧，如果这是零，那将是90
所以就像110度
这样的事情。
让我们尝试角度角度为110。
哦，那还不行。
这里发生了什么？
看起来不像这样。
那么为什么这是一个问题呢？
好吧，首先要了解的是iOS
是零角度，零度不向上，
它在右边。
零角度在右边。
所以如果我们希望这种程度
零直线上升
我们要减去90度
从所有这些角度来看。
所以那90度
与那个角度成90度角
但这也不是很有效。
那仍然不是我们在这里寻找的东西。
好像是从零开始的
但它是顺时针而不是逆时针。
我可以肯定在这里我说的是顺时针错误。
是的，逆时针旋转。
这是怎么回事？
那是不可能的，那不可能发生。
嗯，这是因为在iOS中，
您要在其中绘制的图形坐标系
就在这儿，
在左上角有（0，0），并且上下颠倒。
因此，这将增加Y。
从（0，0）开始
随着我们来到这里，Y越来越大。
您习惯的不是笛卡尔坐标
从您的三角学课。
这不是（0，0），这里是（0，0）。
因此，由于整个过程都是颠倒的，
顺时针和逆时针
也正朝着相反的方向发展。
所以我们实际上需要这个起始角度，终止角度
而且我们也希望顺时针为真。
因此，即使我们确实走了相反的方向，
我们不得不说顺时针是真的。
可以肯定的是，这正是我们想要的。
现在，在下一个讲座中，我们将开始对此进行动画处理。
举例来说，我们仍然让它从零开始，
但是随着时间的流逝，
从110、150开始，
200，
300，
滴答作响350
几乎提高了360倍。
所以我们要为这个角度做动画
下降到零。
这将在下一次演讲中
当我们谈论动画时。
我们要在动画中谈论的第一件事
给Views设置动画。
意见来来去去，
他们越来越大。
有时候他们在做特别的事情
就像CardView可能会翻转一样。
好的，可以做3D旋转来翻转。
现在，查看动画的方式不同。
形状是动画的，它们直接为自己设置动画。
视图通过其修改器进行动画处理。
因此，要了解如何为视图设置动画，
我们将不得不花一点时间来动画
并讨论什么是ViewModifier。
现在，您一直在使用ViewModifiers
到目前为止，在记忆的整个地方，
AspectRatio，填充，字体，前景颜色。
所有这些都是ViewModifiers。
他们修改一个视图并返回一个新的视图
那是您调用它们的View的修改版本。
这就是ViewModifiers所做的。
现在，大多数修饰符，不是全部，而是大多数，
可能只是转过身来实现
并在View协议中调用一个非常重要的功能，
通过扩展名添加到View协议
称为修饰符。
View中的此功能修饰符，
需要一个论点
这本质上是实现
ViewModifier协议。
所以这里aspectRatio 2/3
由于空间原因，我放弃了合适的人选，
但是aspectRatio 2/3
可能会执行类似调用View的操作，
在您将AspectRatio发送到的同一视图上，
就是说点修饰符，
AspectModifier是2/3的某种结构。
因此，让我们谈谈ViewModifier协议是什么。
顾名思义，您几乎可以猜到。
它只有一个功能
而唯一起作用的就是拿点东西
并对其进行修改以生成一个View。
例如，您可以调整空间
提供aspectRatio 2/3，
或ViewModifier可以在外部添加一些填充。
这就是我确定的填充ViewModifier。
那么该代码对于协议来说是什么样的呢？
这就是协议ViewModifier。
第一行关联类型Content。
再次，你们阅读了阅读作业，我希望
并且您了解什么是关联类型内容
是不在乎协议。
协议，就像功能和类型一样
他们也不在乎，
但它们的语法是关联类型Content，
而不是您在struct上看到的尖括号。
因此，ViewModifier协议不必关心
称为内容。
真的不在乎Content是什么类型。
好吧，现在，一旦您了解了，
我们可以看一下ViewModifier中的唯一函数，
这是身体。
身体接受了无关紧要的内容，
我们真的不在乎那是什么，
它返回非常重要的一些视图。
在那个身体里面，只需要吸收内容
那是给它的
然后以某种方式组成一个View并将其返回。
现在，当您在View上调用点修饰符时，
通过的内容
是将“发送点的视图”修改器发送到的视图，对吗？
您调用的点修饰符所在的视图，
这就是内容。
这样就可以使任何ViewModifier
用点修饰符调用
将获得作为内容调用的视图。
这就是为什么我们说它修改了该视图。
它将创建一个新的视图
使用该视图，您会将其作为内容发送到。
是的，让我们来看一个例子
使这一切更加具体。
假设我想拥有一个ViewModifier
像我们的文字幽灵一样使用任何视图
或任何查看图像的任何内容，
并对其进行了修改，使其看起来像卡。
基本上将其卡住。
这就是我们想要构建的。
现在听起来这是一个非常复杂的修饰符。
这比仅在其周围填充填充更加复杂
或类似的东西。
它实际上是一个非常简单的修饰符，
但从概念上讲，这是有道理的。
现在在我们的应用中，我们甚至不一定需要修饰符
之所以这样，是因为我们只有一种观点
曾经被证伪，
但您可以想象一个应用中有一些卡片
上面有图片，有一些表情符号，
有些只是文字或其他内容，其他抽认卡，
但他们都有相同的卡。
能够对任何视图进行梳理可能很有意义。
这是代码的样子。
第一行实际上是
我们如何称呼修饰符。
例如，如果我们想进行卡片化
我们的幽灵文本，我们会说点修饰符，
那个非常重要的View功能
参数是ViewModifier。
现在我要叫我的ViewModifier，
您可以在下一行看到struct Cardify结构。
我将其称为Cardify，它实际上需要一个参数。
我们将讨论这一点。
但最终，尽管如此，我实际上还是想说
文字点成Cardify，
就像我说的是点前景颜色，点填充
我想说点Cardify。
我不想说点修饰符Cardify。
所以在下一张幻灯片上
我们将展示如何从点修饰符Cardify得到
点Cardify。
但现在，让我们专注于
我们将如何实现Cardify ViewModifier
因为这一定要带上文字幽灵
并对其进行修改，将其转换为新的视图
看起来像卡。
这就是这件事要做的。
我想看的第一件事是Content参数
在ViewModifier中添加到该主体函数。
我把它出现的所有地方都变黄了，
这是对身体的争论。
您可以在顶部看到Text鬼魂是那个Content是什么
然后也往下看ZStack
我嵌入该内容，它是一个视图
并将其嵌入到我的ZStack中
在同一地方，我会将其放回旧代码中。
所以现在要获取任何视图并将其嵌入到此处
在我的ZStack卡上。
那么您是否知道这将如何修改视图
您将其发送到看起来像卡片。
现在，这里要注意的一件事是
该ViewModifier需要一些信息，
需要知道卡是面朝上还是面朝下。
这是一个结构，所以我只添加一个var isFaceUp
我们知道，如果您有一个var且未初始化，
然后谁创建这个结构，
在最上面
它需要指定它的值。
所以希望这是您熟悉的样子
当您执行这些修饰符时，
显然很多人都在争论
前景色采用一种颜色
填充可能会占用顶部或底部
以及要填充的点数和所有其他这些参数。
这些只是要放在ViewModifier中进行填充，
例如。
所以点修饰符，那个函数，它返回一个View，
返回符合View的内容
这将在这里使用身体的紫色内容
绘制视图。
现在修饰符不会直接返回此紫色代码
返回另一个也是View的东西，
但是那是另外一回事
将使用此紫色代码绘制绘制的内容。
如此简单。
点修饰符将仅用于使用ViewModifier，
将其发送给身体的视图
它会得到任何必要的内置
并作为要使用的新视图返回。
然后当然，因为那是一个视图，
我们可以给它发送另一个修饰符
以及另一个修饰符，等等
斯威夫特在跟踪方面非常聪明
修改，修改，修改时
这样它就可以做动画之类的事情
那么我们如何从这种文本点修饰符语法中获得
点上Cardify，
因为这就是我们想要点Cardify的原因。
真的很容易，您实际上知道如何执行此操作。
我将创建View协议的扩展，
添加功能cardify
卡片化显然会返回一些视图
它只会返回自我点修饰符
Cardify的
请记住，这是View的扩展，
所以自我就是观点。
所以我当然可以在自身上调用点修饰符
并将其传递给正确的ViewModifier，
在这种情况下，我们的Cardify。
好吧，让我们去实现这个
在我们的记忆应用程序中。
在此演示中，我们的目标是使所有View，
包括我们的幽灵和吃豆人都可以被证成
这意味着当它面朝上时将其周围环绕
或者只是在面朝下时将其拉回。
让我们通过想象开始这个演示
如果有这个修饰符，我们的代码将是什么样子。
让我们在此处留出一些空间，以便我们了解发生了什么。
我现在要把我们的卡的一部分
会被气化的
就是馅饼和文字。
我们将把它们与代码分开
这实际上是在做卡片化。
然后我们要拿这个ZStack
里面有我们想要的东西，
然后我要说点Cardify来进行卡片化。
当然，持牌人需要知道
这个东西是否正视。
所以我要过去那面朝上
我们将看到如何指定
一点点。
现在这段代码就是这样
实际上是进行卡片化对吧？
将RoundedRectangles放在后面或前面。
只是要把它剪下来
然后将其放入Cardify ViewModifier中。
在我去那之前
我最终确实希望这样说，
但是我们知道ViewModifiers
正在调用称为修饰符的此View函数
那么您只需指定所需的ViewModifier。
因此，我们将创建ViewModifier来做到这一点，
我将其称为Cardify
而且当然必须要把脸朝上
作为争论。
这就是这个问题的解决者真正要做的
这最终将成为我们要创建的功能
只是这一行而已。
所以我们将其注释掉并将其放回去
一旦我们添加了一个称为衬套的衬套。
但这就是要做的
当然，它说未解析的标识符Cardify，
我们必须编写执行此ViewModifier的代码。
因此，让我们跳过去。
文件，新文件。
这不是SwiftUI视图，而是ViewModifier。
因此，我们将点击此处，我​​们将转到此处，
我将其称为Cardify
那是我的新修饰符的名称。
注意它没有放在正确的位置。
这是一个很好的例子。
我不想在顶部的这个蓝色的东西。
我要在这里，这个黄色的文件夹
我希望这是同一个地方
这个黄色文件夹在这里。
所以希望大家都记得这样做
这样您就不会到处都是文件
他们不应该。
因此，创建Cardify。
这是Cardify。
现在，当然，ViewModifiers很大程度上是UI的东西，
所以我们不说在那儿导入Foundation，
并创建一个ViewModifier，非常简单。
结构Cardify，这是一个ViewModifier
当我们这样做时，我们将立即得到一个错误
表示Cardify不符合协议ViewModifier。
该协议仅具有一个功能，
它称为主体，它以内容为参数。
此处的此内容是无关紧要的
从这个协议。
因此协议也可以不在乎。
他们使用该associatedtype语法指定它们
在阅读作业中读到的
所以这可以是任何东西。
这不在乎。
我们将在短短一秒钟内讨论一下。
那当然是一个ViewModifier
它正在修改一个视图，然后返回一些新的视图
那是它的修改版本。
所以这个论点在这里，
只是为了提醒您幻灯片
当我们在这里回叫修改器Cardify时，
要求我们修改的内容
将成为我们称之为修改器的任何视图。
因此，我们将在ZStack上调用修饰符。
所以在这种情况下，我们的梳理机内部
内容将是ZStack。
这始终是您在其上调用点修饰符的视图。
那么，这里发生了什么？
在这里，我们只需要创建修改后的视图，
换句话说，一个卡片化视图。
所以我只是要粘贴我们以前拥有的东西
当然，这仍然必须在ZStack中
因为我们仍然有这些RoundedRectangles
彼此堆叠。
因此，让我们继续进行。
我们这里有一些未定义的东西，
如cornerRadius和edgeLineWidth。
那些都在这里，那就是绘制常量。
我们不再需要它们了
因为我们使用卡片化来制作卡片。
因此，我们将其弹出此处。
这解决了我们的大多数问题。
我们确实知道我们必须通过这是空间
作为这里的一个论点
Cardify需要知道它是否面朝上
所以它会有一个var isFaceUp这是一个布尔值
我不会把它设置为等于
因此，只要有人在这里创建Cardify，
他们必须告诉我isFaceUp的价值是什么
然后我要在里面使用这个isFaceUp
任何时候我想检查一下我是否正对面。
现在，这是匹配的东西。
isMatched确实不属于Cardify。
匹配与我们的纸牌游戏有关。
此Cardify可以Cardify任何视图，
不只是我们的纸牌游戏中的“观看次数”。
这可以使卡面朝上，面朝下在任何视图上。
所以我们想保持通用。
我们不希望它与应用程序的其余部分绑定在一起。
这是一件很好的可重用的事情
我们实际上可以使用其他游戏-
假设我们写了其他游戏
卡片上有一些文字，卡片上有图像
卡上的表情符号和表情符号都混在同一个应用中。
好吧，我们可以使用Cardify对所有这些东西进行Cardify。
但是我们真的无法找到匹配项
因为匹配特定于此应用，所以请记住。
然后我们要在这里做的最后一件事
显然，此内容需要在此处的某个位置。
好吧，我要把它准确地放在以前的位置。
只是为了内容。
内容就是视图，ZStack
该修饰符将被发送到此处。
所以我要拿这个
它会在这里弹出。
现在我完成了。
这是一个使用此内容的ViewModifier，
点修饰符发送到此处的任何视图
并将其与RoundedRectangles放在ZStack中
或者，如果它面朝上，就这样做，等等。
这是使该内容有意义的东西。
做了什么，让我们回到这里。
让我们继续运行，看看是否可行。
似乎卡的背面正在工作。
让我们尝试一下。
哦，这很好。
现在这里有一个问题
如果我有比赛
然后我点击另一张卡片，哦，这些卡片不会消失。
那是因为我从那里拿走了匹配的东西。
因此，我们必须解决此问题。
我们要解决的另一件事是
我们想要更好的语法点cardify。
因此，让我们先修复更好的语法
然后我们将解决匹配卡的问题
仍被包括在这里
什么时候应该把它们拿走。
可以证卡的功能
这只是我们将要添加的扩展名。
这显然最有意义
把它放在这个文件中
因为这是Cardify ViewModifier所在的位置。
所以这是我们想要扩展View的地方
具有func cardify的功能。
现在cardify也将必须采取
是否面对面作为争论
只是要归还该卡片化视图
真的很容易实现。
只会自称
self是一个View，我们是View的扩展，
修饰符，我们要给它一个Cardify
isFaceUp是传递给我们的isFaceUp。
就是这样。
简单如馅饼。
无双关语。
我们在这里将cardify变成了一个不错的小功能
我们可以像这样调用任何视图。
您不需要这种稍微笨重的方式
这对您来说应该像字体
一些点largeTitle，前景色颜色。
匹配的卡片没有消失的事实又如何呢？
我只要做这张整张卡片
如果卡面朝上或尚未匹配。
该卡面朝上，或者我尚未匹配，
然后繁荣，我要把这张卡放在那儿。
不然我只想要空格
这正是我们以前所拥有的。
现在这给了一个错误，说
函数声明了不透明的返回类型，是的，某些视图，
但没有return return语句。
哦是的
这里没有return语句。
我想我可以说归还可以解决这个问题，
但是在其他情况下呢？
如果没有，我们有这个
在这种情况下，我们不返回任何东西。
所以那不好，我要解决这个问题
以一种新颖有趣的方式，
我就是要把它变成一个ViewBuilder。
如果我将此功能转换为ViewBuilder，
那么现在它被解释为视图列表。
是的，如果要确定某些视图是进入还是退出，
但这是视图列表。
要么成为ZStack，要么成为View，
否则将为EmptyView。
看起来没有错误，就这么简单。
我们有ViewBuilder。
在这里运行它，让我们尝试看看。
可以了
让我们比赛，哦，拿走了他们
因为这不是真的，他们就走了。
现在我们可以做的另一件事
并确保我们的cardify确实有效，
让我们尝试其他一些视图，而不是使用ZStack。
像个圆圈怎么样
让我们继续将画布带回此处。
我们可以看到这一点。
是的，看那个。
这是放在卡片上的圆。
我们甚至可以做圆
上面有一点填充，对吗？
或者，也许我们将在这里放入一个胶囊。
那是另一个内置的Shape Capsule。
如果您想知道的话，那就是胶囊形状。
我们可以放一些类似Text的东西。
世界，您好，看得出来。
所以cardify是通用的修饰符ViewModifier
我们构建的可以修改任何View的视图。
好吧，这很好
我们已经完成了所有ViewModifier的工作
因为下一场我们要讲的动画
当涉及到动画视图时，
不是像这个Pie那样的形状，而是为Views本身设置动画，
都是关于ViewModifiers的。
他们真的只是在给ViewModifiers动画，
我们实际上并未为View本身设置动画。
我们将在下一个讲座中研究
并了解如何为这张卡制作动画。
卡上有很多他们想要的动画。
例如，他们想翻身。
那是一张卡片想要的好动画，
所以我们把这张卡片化
到ViewModifier，以便我们下次对其进行动画处理。
今天就是这样。
那我再和你谈谈。
-[旁白]有关更多信息，请访问我们@ stanford.edu。
(air whooshing)
- [Narrator] Stanford University.
- [Instructor] All righty, lecture five.
Stanford CS193P spring of 2020.
Today we are going to start
off with a little demo
of access control in Memorize.
Access control is something
you've all already read about
in your reading assignments
and we actually used access
control a little tiny bit
in Memorize, but now it's
time to apply access control
to all of Memorize and
to use it going forward
and you should be using it
in all your SwiftUI programming
forever going forward.
After the demo, we're gonna come back
and talk a little bit about ViewBuilder.
Very important, pretty
simple little concept
and I have mentioned it a
few times in past lecture,
but now we just wanna clearly clarify
what ViewBuilder is all about.
Then we're gonna go to
the main topic of the day,
which is Shapes.
What if I want to draw my View
instead of making my
View out of other Views?
How do I do that?
And we will do a demo in
Memorize where we add a Shape,
that little pie that's behind the emoji
that you saw in lecture one,
and then we're gonna move
on to the topic of animation
and we're gonna realize that
animation is super important
in a mobile app and also
that it's super easy in Swift
almost just for free in some ways,
but when we start talking about animation
we're gonna rapidly get to this point
where we need to talk
about this other concept
called ViewModifiers.
ViewModifiers are fundamental
to how we're building these Views
and you've been using
ViewModifiers all over the place
and probably just not even
realizing you're doing it
and we're gonna dive into
exactly what's going on
in all that SwiftUI code
that you're writing.
By the way, following along
is not required this week
by the homework.
In fact, your homework this week
is not even going to be Memorize.
It's time for you to
write your own application
from scratch.
But this access control stuff
that I'm going to do right now
is something that you're
gonna have to apply
to all your code.
So following along with Memorize
might be a good learning experience.
And later in the quarter it's
quite possible we'll come back
to Memorize as a homework thing,
you're not done with Memorize yet.
And in that case I will
do my best to make it
so that the code that I'm
gonna show you this week
does not have to be included
in future homework submissions
of Memorize.
I can't a hundred percent promise that,
but I'm hoping to make that be the case.
Having said that, a lot of students find
that following along or
really helps them learn,
so I guess I actually
recommend that you do that.
And so let's start by diving
into this whole access
control change to Memorize.
Now, we've already used act
as control once in Memorize
only once, right here, private.
And access control is about
controlling the access
that different structs
have to each other's vars.
And by making this
Model completely private
in our ViewModel here,
we've forced the ViewModel
to make this var cards
so that the View could get the Cards,
and of course we want to have this Intent
so that if someone wants
to change the Model,
they have to express their
intent, how they want to do it
and that was good, that made this private.
However we could have taken
this one step further.
In our Model, the Cards themselves
probably want to be private.
Why is that?
Well we don't want anyone going in here
and mucking with these Cards.
Setting them isMatched
or even setting them face up or face down.
Whether a Card is matched
is purely in the purview
of this MemoryGame Model.
Only it knows whether
Cards should be matched
and all that logic is
in here in choose card.
So we really would want
to make this private.
But making this private is
actually gonna be a problem.
If we go back here and
look at this line of code
and compile it now with
that private in there,
you can see we get an error.
It says cards is inaccessible
due to private protection level.
And indeed the Cards are now private
and so the ViewModel is no longer allowed
to access this var.
But the ViewModel does need to access
at least to read the Cards.
How else are we gonna
show the Cards in our UI?
So we can't really have this be private,
but we can use a different
access control level
which is set.
Private set means setting this is private,
but reading it is not.
And that's exactly what
we want in this case.
We want people to able
to look at our Cards
so they can put them in
the UI, display them.
However, when it comes
to changing the Cards,
we definitely want that
reserved for ourself.
So private set, a real common
access control to want to set.
Now access control is not just
something we set on our vars.
This is something we can
also set on our functions
and our own internal computer vars.
For example,
indexOfTheOneAndOnlyFaceUpCard
here in our Model, that's
purely a private thing.
That's private logic how
we figure out how to do
our matching game.
This definitely wants to be private.
We certainly wouldn't
want anyone setting this,
that could totally mess us up
and we really don't even
want someone looking at it
because if they started looking at it
they might depend on it
and then now I have to always
use this particular strategy
to do my logic I might not want,
so that's what we have
to keep this private.
Of course choose can't be private.
It is the way that people play our game
and our init doesn't wanna be private.
You are allowed to have private inits.
It'd be a rare circumstance,
but you could have init's only
used inside of your struct
to create maybe private instances
that this is going to use.
Now struct Card is kind
of interesting here.
You probably are thinking,
oh, private set, private set,
private set, private set.
We don't want anybody to be setting these.
However, the only way you can get a Card
outside of our Model
is through this Array.
And this Array is already private set.
This is a value type.
The actual Cards are in this Array.
When someone calls this var to get this,
they're getting a copy
and that copy is read only
because of private set.
So since there's no way for
anyone to get a writeable Card,
it's perfectly fine for us
to leave these vars this way.
Okay, what about back in
our ViewModel over here?
Clearly access to the Model.
This doesn't have to be private.
It's read only anyway
'cause it's a read only var.
Definitely Intents have be non-private.
How else will people express their intent?
But this createMemoryGame,
this static func
that probably wants to be private.
We likely do not want other people,
especially our View, to
be creating a MemoryGame.
Creating a MemoryGame, creating our Model,
that's something we do.
In your homework you have
to have a new game function.
You might well be creating
a new MemoryGame here,
but that's gonna have to
happen in your ViewModel
because there's no way
that Views, for example,
could take responsibility
for creating a Model.
So the ViewModel really wants
this to be private function.
What about in our View?
So here's our View over here.
Now let's look at CardView.
It's kind of an interesting one.
It's got these drawing
constants down here.
Those definitely can be private.
There's really no reason
that anyone would be, they're
lets anyway, but there's no reason someone
will want to be accessing
these things down here,
so this can definitely be private.
This var body has to be non-private
'cause the system is going to call that.
That's, how it gets the body for our View
and it's gonna be calling
in any time it needs to
to find out how to draw this CardView.
But this little helper function
that we call from inside
our GeometryReader,
there's no reason for
that to be public, okay?
Only we call that from our own code
inside of CardView here.
What about this var?
Can this be private?
No, because when we create a CardView,
we are required to give
this thing an initial value,
so we have to be able to access it here.
If we made this private,
then we wouldn't be able to
set it when we created it
and this will be uninitialized
and that was not allowed in Swift.
What about up here?
Well, again, var body has to be public
and also the ViewModel here
is going to have to be public
because for example, when
we create our previewer,
we're specifying the ViewModel,
and over here in our little SceneDelegate,
when we're creating the main
View of our window of our app,
we're expressing it here.
So again, this has to be public for that.
What about down here in Grid?
So in Grid, it's an
interesting case in Grid.
Do these vars have to be public?
Well, not really because we
have this public initializer
that sets these vars.
So we could make these fully private
and that would be perfectly fine.
These vars only needed to be public
if you're gonna ask people
to initialize them directly.
But since we have an
initializer to initialize them,
they don't need to be public.
Probably would want these to be private.
Var body has to be public, of course.
But again, these little
body helper functions,
they don't need to be public.
How about here in GridLayout?
So we've got GridLayout.
Of course we need the constructor
or the initializer to be public
and we need the itemSize
and location to be public,
otherwise, how are people gonna use it?
But these vars, very important
to make these private set.
Why is it so important to make
these three vars private set?
These three vars are calculated
from the initializer,
the values that come through
in the initializer are here.
And if we didn't make these private set,
someone might think that
they can reset this size var
and that these would automatically reset.
But that's not true.
Once you initialize the
GridLayout, it's fixed forever.
So we want people to know that
they can only read these
values out of here.
You can't set this and
expect these to change
or something as such.
So that's a case where access control
actually helps people understand
how to use this thing.
Okay, obviously our firstIndex,
we want that public.
We're adding that to all Arrays.
Same thing with our var only.
We're doing that public.
So that's it.
That's how we got our access
control set up in Memorize.
Every time we add new functions,
and when you do this in your homework,
you should definitely be putting privates
wherever things should be private.
Now many of you are already
working on your homework.
You haven't done this yet,
I encourage you to go do it.
We're not gonna hold
you accountable for it
in assignment number two,
but we definitely will in
assignment number three.
Let's run our app
and make sure that putting
all this private worked
and it did.
Sometimes you'll run your
app and you'll realize,
oh, I made that private but
this thing actually needs it.
And then you have to decide,
does it really want us to access that?
And if so, should it be
private set or just private?
So that's it for our little
access control foray.
Let's get back to our slides
and talk more about ViewBuilder.
So ViewBuilder is based
on a general technology
that was added to Swift recently
to support list-oriented syntax.
There's a lot of things that
are expressed as a list,
like HTML for example, it's just a list.
A paragraph and then an embedded thing
and then another paragraph,
header or whatever,
they're just listed on the page.
And so it'd be nice in Swift
to be able to represent these
somewhat native list-oriented syntaxes.
And once you have this mechanism
then you rapidly realize,
oh, there's a lot of places
where we just want a list of View,
like the front of our Cards.
We just wanna list the
two RoundedRectangles
and the emoji.
So ViewBuilder lets developers do this
and @ViewBuilder is the key word.
It's again, not part of the language.
@ViewBuilder is like @Published
or @ObservedObject,
it's the thing that's based
on these other technologies.
But @ViewBuilder, this
keyword can be tagged
onto any function that returns some View.
So as long as a function
returns some View,
you can tag that function
with @ViewBuilder
and now the compiler will interpret
what's in the curly
braces of that function
to be a list of Views, instead
of just arbitrary code,
a list of Views.
That's how ViewBuilder works.
Now that function that you're tagging
with @ViewBuilder,
it returns some View
which is a single View.
So ViewBuilder, that's why
it's called ViewBuilder,
it builds that list of
Views into a single View.
That one View that it combines it to
many times is going to be a TupleView.
So if there's two to 10
Views lifted in there,
it's gonna be a TupleView.
TupleView has up to 10 don't cares,
which are the 10 Views in there.
And notice it is limited to 10.
So if you started having
more than 11 Views,
you're gonna have to
break it up into groups,
TupleViews of TupleViews to
get that many Views in there.
It's pretty rare to imagine
having more than 10 Views
just listed straight in a row.
You're almost certainly
going to be breaking that up
with some kind of
sub-Views like CardViews,
the sub-View of our
EmojiGameView, et cetera.
So it's not really much of a
limitation but it is there.
The other kind of View could be maybe
as a ConditionalContent View,
under-bar ConditionalContent View,
and that's what the View creates
when there's an if-else in there.
Remember that the if-elses
inside of ViewBuilder
are just to choose which Views
get included in the list,
like whether it's the
front of the CardViews
or the back of the CardView.
And so that's going to create
this ConditionalContent View
which just has the predicate
to test against isFaceUp
and then it has the two Views,
might be a TupleView or some other View
that it's going to choose from.
Could even be an EmptyView
that's allowed as well.
I don't know why you would
want that necessarily,
but you could have it.
But the most important
thing to remember is that
it can be any combination of these things.
So you could have a TupleView
or one of the things in the
TupleView is a conditional View
and inside that conditional View
there's another TupleView, et cetera.
And that lets you build these
kind of arbitrarily complex
conditional lists of Views
and that's really what
this thing is all about.
Now note that some of this ViewBuilder API
is not fully public.
Like see that under-bar
ConditionalContent,
Obviously something with an
under-bar in the front of it
is not ready for prime
time, it's not fully public.
I'll bet if you look that
up in the documentation
you won't even find anything there,
but that's okay, because
we actually don't care
what kind of Views these are.
TupleViews, ConditionalContent, whatever,
all that we care is that
it's some View, right?
We can only tag a function
that returns some View
with this thing.
That's all we care about.
All of these things are some View
and so that's good enough for us.
Again, any function, also
read-only computed vars
can also be tagged with this ViewBuilder
and tagging it on there just
makes it so that function
is interpreted as a ViewBuilder.
Here's a sample from our Memorize.
Let's say that I wanted to
factor out the front of the Card,
those two RoundedRectangles
and the Text that you see here
into its own little function.
Well I could have func, front of card,
it returns some View
and in here I would normally
have to put it in a Group
or something like that,
but instead I can just
mark it @ViewBuilder
and now the curly braces within there
is going to be interpreted
as a list of Views.
And I could have if-thens
and stuff in here,
if I wanted to do the whole
Card inside here I could
and have the if isFaceUp,
all that stuff perfectly allowed.
This is just a list of
Views with those if-thens
allowed in there.
This particular green code
would return a TupleView
where it's three don't cares
are RoundedRectangle,
RoundedRectangle, Text.
Of course there are two
TupleViews with eight don't cares
and nine or this will
be the one with three.
And again we don't care that
it's doing a TupleView there.
Absolutely don't care.
All we care is this some View.
Now you could also use this @ViewBuilder
to mark parameters to functions
that are themselves functions
that return some View.
For example, our viewForItem
argument to Grid, right?
That was a function that took an Item
and returned a View, and
that would be eligible
to be marked with @ViewBuilder.
Now we didn't do that in Grid
and I'll talk about that
in a second, why we didn't,
but someone who does do
that is GeometryReader
and HStack and VStack and
ForEach they all do this,
but let's look at what the declaration
of GeometryReader's initializer
probably looks like.
You've got GeometryReader, right?
It's got this don't care Content,
which is constrained to be a View.
So the initializer for GeometryReader
we know takes content,
this curly brace thing,
that gives you the GeometryProxy,
the thing that we get the size out of,
and it returns Content that's some View.
So since this content argument
is a function that returns some View,
it can be marked @ViewBuilder
which GeometryReader does.
It marks it @ViewBuilder.
That means that what's
inside your GeometryReader's,
little curly braces, is a list of Views,
is going to be interpreted
as a list of Views.
It's as simple as that.
And it's usually up to
things like GeometryReader,
Hstack, VStack,
to decide whether the argument
that you're passing them
makes sense to be a list of Views.
And for those guys that's
what they determine.
Now, you might ask, why
didn't we do this in Grid?
Grid is asking you to provide
a View for a certain item
and we pass a function.
Why didn't we say @ViewBuilder
for our View for item argument in Grid?
Well the answer had its part
to do with this thing where
ViewBuilder's still kind of private.
It's implementation for example,
has no way to extract the Views
from a TupleView, ConditionalContent,
it's just you can't get them out of there.
So there's no way Grid could
know what they all are.
That's not public in the
current @ViewBuilder.
I'm sure this will be made public
and eventually you could do it
and then maybe it might make
sense to have Grid's argument,
but even then Grid is a
two-dimensional Array.
That's usually gonna be
a fair number of Views.
It's unlikely you're
gonna be listing them,
especially if you're gonna
have 10 or less of them,
possible, but unlikely.
So the fact that Grid
gets in bed with ForEach
and represents it the
same way ForEach does
is probably just fine.
Just before we leave ViewBuilder,
I'd just like to reiterate this.
This slide is nothing new.
Things that are marked ViewBuilder
are just a list of Views.
Yes, there's conditional in there
to see whether you include
a View in the list,
but there's just a list of Views.
So no vars can be declared in there,
you can't have arbitrary code.
Anytime you have something
that's a ViewBuilder,
it's just this list of Views
with the if-thens in there
to pick which Views.
Main topic of the day, Shape.
Shape is a protocol.
It inherits from View,
so all Shapes are Views.
So you can always put a
Shape in a ZStack or whatever
as we saw,
RoundedRectangle, we threw
it in there, no problem.
There are of course built in common Shapes
like RoundedRectangle, there's Circle,
there's Capsule which is a
kind-of oval sort of thing
and other ones in there.
Now Shapes draw themselves by default
by filling themselves with
the current foreground color.
We saw this with the backs of our Cards.
They take a RoundedRectangle,
it just by default fills.
But we also learned that
we can call stroke or fill
with arguments to change
the way the Shape looks.
Now I wanna talk about fill and stroke
and the arguments that
can be passed to it.
It might have looked like,
when we did our Memorize code,
that the argument that's passed
to fill is actually a Color
because you'll remember that
the second RoundedRectangle
from the back, actually no,
the rectangle all the way
in the back, is white.
And then we put the
stroked one on top of it.
So that white one we
said fill Color.white.
So it seemed like, oh, fill takes a Color.
But in fact fills argument is not a Color
and I'm gonna take this
opportunity with fill and stroke
to talk about another feature in Swift
called generic functions.
You already know about generic types
like Array and like our MemoryGame,
it has CardContent as a don't care.
Well, functions can have
don't cares as well.
They can be generic as well.
And they do this similar kind of syntax.
You can see that fill
has this don't care S,
what to fill with type S,
see that's a type of S,
and it's constraining it
so that it's not a full don't care
it's kind of like a care a little bit
where that S has to implement
the ShapeStyle protocol.
So this ShapeStyle protocol,
we're not gonna talk about it,
but if you implement
this ShapeStyle protocol,
then you can be used to
fill or stroke a Shape.
What kinds of things implement ShapeStyle?
Well Color, obviously we know
'cause we've called fill with Color,
but also ImagePaint,
which takes JPEG image
and tiles it in there to paint with
as if it were a paintbrush of
that image just painting it.
Also there are Gradients,
angular and linear Gradients
that show a band of colors or whatever.
So these things are all quite different,
Color, Gradient, ImagePainting,
very different things,
and really fill doesn't
care what they are.
That's why S is a don't care.
But it does care 'cause they
all implement this ShapeStyle
'cause if they don't
implement the ShapeStyle
then a Shape doesn't
really know how to use them
to do the fill and stroke.
Again, I'm mostly showing you this,
yes, so that you can know
that you can fill with Images
or Gradients or Colors,
but also so you should realize
that there are these generic functions,
functions that have don't cares
as the types of some of their arguments.
What if you wanna create your own Shape?
You don't wanna use
RoundedRectangle, Circle,
whatever, you want your own Shape.
Well, the Shape protocol uses an extension
to implement View's
body var for you, right?
'Cause Shape inherits from
View, so Shape is a View.
So it would have to
implement the body var.
All Views have to implement that body var.
But Shape implements that for you.
The protocol and
extension of that protocol
implements it for you.
However, Shape introduces a new func
that you are required to implement.
It's called path in rect.
So this function path in
rect is going to just return
something called a Path.
Now a Path has a whole
bunch of functions on it,
like line to and arc and Bezier curve.
All these things that
let you essentially draw
like you're drawing with a pen.
And so you're going to build some Path
by drawing with this
pen and return it here.
Now, once you return it, now
Shape has all it needs to know
to do what it does,
which is provide a Shape that
can be stroked and filled.
Now this is best shown, how
this works, with a demo.
So we're gonna go back to Memorize
and implement that little pie.
If you remember from our first lecture
there was that little pie and it animated
and it kind of ran the clock down
so that if you match the card fast enough,
you got extra points.
So we're gonna draw that
pie in our memory game.
We're not gonna animate it yet.
Animation is our next topic.
We will get back to that.
So today we're just learning
how to create our own Shape
by building that pie.
I've taken a screenshot of
that video of the game in play
so that we can see what
it is we're shooting for.
We're trying to build this
little pie chart thing
that maybe looks like
a Pac-Man or something
behind our ghost.
And there's no such Shape
built in to SwiftUI,
this kind of Pac-Man Shape,
so we're gonna have to
build this ourselves.
But before we start
building this custom Shape,
let's just try and get a circle
behind this ghost right here.
'Cause we know there is
this built-in Circle,
just like there's a big built
in RoundedRectangle here.
So to do that, pretty straightforward.
Here's our View, here's our CardView.
Right here and here is
yep, here's the background.
Here's where our emoji is
and this Circle kind of just wants to live
right in between here,
right between the
background and the emojis.
So let's see.
This just works.
Maybe this is all we need to get started.
All right, let's click.
Oh that's actually getting there.
Take a look.
Oh, that's pretty close.
Now it's not quite right.
It's a little too close
to the edges there,
there's supposed to be a little gap,
and this color is a little
too bright of orange,
but it's in the ballpark.
Now we could go back
here and try and fix this
and then run again and then fix some more
and then run again and tweak it some more.
But that's a little tedious
and of course we have a
much better tool for that,
which is our canvas over here
and we can just resume and
see what our thing looks like
and it looks like...
Oh no, all the cards are face down.
Which kind of makes sense
because that's how game starts,
but it's kind of useless to me
to have all these cards face down.
I really want at least one
of these cards to be face up
so I can be working on this.
How do we do that?
Turns out that this
code down at the bottom
that I pushed out of the way,
it's not as scary as
maybe I made it out to be
by pushing it out of the way.
This is really just a static
var that is of type, some View
that is returning this
whole View to preview our
EmojiMemoryGameView.
And right now we're creating one
an EmojiMemoryGameView.
and we're giving it this ViewModel
that we just created on the fly.
But there's no reason
that we couldn't just
take this out of here,
put it in a variable, I'll call it game,
ask that game to choose one of the Cards,
how about choose the
first card in the game,
something like that,
and then use that game here
as the thing that we're going to preview.
Of course we have to return
since we don't have a one line function,
and voila, right away we're
seeing the face-up Card
and I could maybe have
it choose the third Card
and now it's showing me the third Card.
So I could have it pick a couple of Cards.
Of course, if I pick three Cards,
then it's going play the game and match.
But this is perfect for our needs.
We can go back up here and
start working on this Circle
and try to make it look more
like we're intending over here.
Let's start by trying to
get it in from the edge
a little bit so it doesn't
smash into the edge.
We know how to do that.
Just put some padding around this Circle.
Well, now, that's not quite
what we're looking for.
A little too much padding.
How about if we just, I don't know,
put less padding around there?
Yeah, I'm pretty happy with that.
Although my ghost there is a little big,
I don't think I wanna smash
in right up at the edge there.
So maybe I'll go down to my
control panel of constants here
and change this to like 0.7 yeah,
maybe 0.65 no, 70% that looks good.
I don't want this to be too small.
This is the purpose of that
card is really to show this.
So I don't wanna go too small there.
What about this really
kind of vivid orange?
Well, it turns out we can make an orange
that's kinda light or kinda
see through right here
by making it semi-transparent.
And View has an awesome
modifier for that, opacity,
it's called, takes a double between zero,
which means completely transparent
to one, completely opaque.
Now we can go in the
middle, maybe like 70%,
maybe 10% oh it's too light.
30%, 40%, I kinda like 40%.
I think that's what I
ended up with over here.
It's close, something like that.
You can see we've got this
really looking the way we want
except that this is a
Circle instead of our pie.
To do our Pac-Man pie thing,
we just need to replace Circle right here
with our own custom Shape.
So let's do that, let's create that.
I'm gonna go File, New
because we're creating a new thing here.
It is gonna be a SwiftUI View
because Shapes are Views,
but if we pick this template,
we're gonna get that var body
and the Shape protocol
provides that for us.
So we're just gonna pick
Swift file right here,
make sure we put it in the right place.
I'm gonna call it Pie, is
the name of my custom Shape.
Let's create that.
Here we go.
Now of course Shapes are
very much a UI thing,
so we're gonna import
SwiftUI, not Foundation there.
And creating a Shape, so easy, struct Pie.
It conforms to the Shape protocol
just constrains and gains with that,
and it's gonna gain the
fact that it's a View
and it can be filled and
stroked, all kinds of gains,
and the only real constraint
here is this func,
that's called path in rect,
and it returns a Path
that we have to create,
and this Path is just
going to be the edges
of what we're drawing.
So for us it's gonna start
here in the middle and go up,
around here, back to the middle.
That is the Path that we're gonna build.
And we're gonna build that
with functions in Path
like draw a line to here
and draw an arc over here.
We're just gonna combine all those
to make this nice path.
And once we do, Shape we'll
take care of all the rest.
Being able to fill it and all that
is gonna all be taken care of for us.
How do we return this path thing?
I'm just gonna create an empty
one, I'll call it p Path.
That's an empty Path,
and I'm gonna return it.
And in between here I just
have to call functions in Path
that move around, draw the
lines that I wanna draw.
Now what is this rect that's passed to us?
That is the rect in which we're
supposed to fit our Shape.
Now almost all, if not all Shapes
usually use all the space in
the rect that's given to them
and yes, you guessed it,
because Shape is a View,
the rect it's gonna give you here
is the space that was offered to it.
Space offered to it.
We've got this Path, got this rect,
how are we gonna do this?
Let's start by gonna the
center of the rectangle.
So we're gonna be given
this rectangle to draw in.
Let's go right to its
center and start there,
right here, and then we're gonna move up.
So let's start in the middle.
So getting the middle is pretty easy.
I'm just gonna go to the
middle by saying p Path,
that's this Path, dot move to the center.
And center is gonna be a var.
Let center equal.
To get the center I'm just
gonna create a CGPoint.
Now notice that all of
these drawing things,
not just CGFloat, but
CGRect, CGPoint, CGSize
that we saw with GeometryReader,
they all start with CG.
This CG stands for Core Graphics.
That's the underlying graphics system
that all this is built on.
So finding the center of
this rect is really easy.
The X position is just the rect midX
and the Y is the rectangles midY.
So that's it.
We got the center, we're
started already here,
but we haven't drawn anything.
We haven't actually drawn
any lines or anything.
So the next thing we're gonna do
is draw a line from the center up to here.
Now I'm gonna make it so that my Pie,
this starting angle and this ending angle,
can be anything you want.
So you can make your Pie a
small little piece of pie
or big pie pointing in any direction.
So I'm gonna need a couple of vars
One is gonna be my starting angle
and one is my ending angle.
So let's put those vars in our Shape.
This is just a struct.
So he can have vars startAngle,
but what type would the angle be?
Well, you could make it a
CGFloat or something like that,
but there's a really nice
thing in Swift called Angle
and I'll show you that in a second.
So we're gonna make these start
and end angles, the Angles.
What is an Angle?
Let's go ahead and take a look
at it in the documentation.
Here it is, struct
Angle, it's just a struct
It lets you create an Angle
using degrees or using radians.
Hopefully everyone remembers
from trigonometry class
what radians are, right?
Degrees zero to 360
around the circle,
radians it's zero to 2π.
2πr that's the circumference of a circle.
So radians is zero to
2π around the circle.
And notice this Angle's animatable.
That's gonna be nice for us later.
Also it can be hashed,
that means a can be put in
a dictionary or hash table.
We don't need to do that,
but this Angle, very nice
little type for us.
I need to somehow
calculate a start position
up at the top up here,
this little position here,
so that I can draw a
line from here to here.
So I'm gonna draw that line by saying
addLine to the start at the top there.
So I need start.
How about start equals a
point also, so CGPoint.
Let's go ahead and put
this on multiple lines
and have the X on one line
and the Y on another line.
So the X position, horizontal position,
is the center's X plus
the radius of our circle,
which we're gonna have to figure out,
times, and again, I'm
hoping you're remembering
your trigonometry from
eighth grade or ninth grade
or whenever trigonometry
is taught these days,
and I wanna do the cosine
of that start angle,
and I have to do it in radians
because this cosine function
in Swift does radians,
and also I wanna do this
all in CGFloat world,
not in Double's.
And similarly the Y is
just the center dot Y
plus the radius times
the sine of the CGFloat
startAngle dot radians.
And so I need the radius.
What's gonna be the
radius of my circle here?
Well, I could make it the width
or I could make it the height.
I really want it to be
the smaller of the two.
So in this case I definitely
don't wanna have my radius
be half the height of this space
because then it's gonna be way too big.
So I'm gonna pick the smaller
of the width or height
and divide it by two so that it's radius
instead of diameter.
So let's do that and let
our radius equal the minimum
of the rect's width and
the rect's height and
we divide by two.
So I think that's all we need to do
to get up to that point
up at the top over here.
Now we need to go in this big arc.
Okay, turn this arc.
Luckily Path has a function
for arcing as well.
It's called addArc and you
can do it different ways.
I'm gonna choose the simplest one here,
which lets you create an arc
by specifying the center of
the arc, the radius of the arc,
the start angle, and the end angle,
and whether you're going
clockwise around the arc,
or counter-clockwise, right?
So whether we're gonna go
counterclockwise like this
or whether we're gonna
go clockwise like this.
So let's give this center.
We know the center it's
that center radius.
Yep, we know that too.
Start angle?
Yeah, we know the start angle.
End angle?
Yeah, that's this var up here.
This is really easy.
And how about clockwise?
This is a boolean, whether
we're going clockwise,
let's allow people using
us to tell us that too.
So we'll say clockwise is a Bool,
put clockwise down here.
And let's not make them say it though.
We'll have a default, we'll
have a clockwise false.
That happens to be the
way we wanna go, right?
Counter clockwise, so
we'll do clockwise false
work for our Pie.
But this is just a default,
we had to pick one of them,
we might as well pick this one.
That's the arc.
We're almost done with
our little Path here.
It goes around, now it needs
to come back to the middle.
So we need a line back
to the center there.
So that's p dot addLine to the center.
And that is it.
We have done a custom Shape here.
All we had to do was define
this Path and return it,
and we have a custom Shape.
Shape is gonna take
care of everything else,
filling it, stroking it, all that stuff
it knows how to do that.
So let's go back to our View
and where we used Circle right here,
we're gonna use our Pie instead.
So let's do Pie.
Oops, sorry, quit Xcode there.
Let's get our thing back here.
Sorry about that.
We know that Pie has some vars.
I'm gonna initialize the
starting angle and the end angle.
Notice that the clockwise
is an optional one.
We don't have to specify that.
So let's choose to do the
start and end angles here.
Now what angles are we
looking to start at here?
Well, we want to start straight up here
and go counterclockwise over to here.
So the straight up that's
probably Angle dot degrees zero,
and then the end angle,
where are we ending?
We are ending over here.
Well if this is zero and this would be 90
so this would be like what, 110 degrees,
something like that.
Let's try that Angle dot degrees 110.
Oh, that didn't quite work.
What is going on here?
This does not look anything like this.
So why is this a problem?
Well, the first thing to understand in iOS
is that Angle zero,
zero degrees is not up,
it's out to the right.
Angle zero's out to the right.
So if we wanted this to
be in the kind of degrees
where zero is straight up,
we're gonna have to subtract 90 degrees
from all these angles.
So 90 degrees off of that one
and 90 degrees off of that one.
But that didn't really work either.
That's still not what we're
looking for over here.
It looks like it started up here at zero,
but it went clockwise
instead of counterclockwise.
I'm certain over here that
I said clockwise false.
Yeah, counter-clockwise.
What's going on?
That's impossible, that
couldn't possibly be happening.
Well, this is happening because in iOS,
the drawing coordinate
system that you're drawing in
right here,
has (0, 0) in the upper
left and is upside down.
So this is increasing Y.
Starting up here at (0, 0)
Y is getting bigger as we get down here.
It's not Cartesian coordinates
that you're used to
from your trigonometry class.
This is not (0, 0),
this is (0, 0) up here.
So since this whole thing is upside down,
clockwise and counterclockwise
are going the other way as well.
So we actually need this
start angle, end angle,
and we also want clockwise true.
So even though we're really
going the opposite direction,
we're having to say clockwise true.
And sure enough, that has
given us exactly what we want.
Now in the next lecture, we
will start animating this.
For example, we'll have
it still start at zero,
but as the time ticks down,
it'll go from 110, 150,
200,
300,
it's ticking down 350,
times almost up 360 times up.
So we're going to just animate this Angle
going down to zero.
That's all gonna be in the next lecture
when we talk about animation.
The first thing we're gonna
talk about in animation though
is animating Views.
Views are coming and going,
they're getting larger and smaller.
Sometimes they're doing special thing
like a CardView might flip over.
Okay, kind of do a 3D
rotation to flip over.
Now View animation is
not done in the same way.
Shapes are animated, they
animate themselves directly.
Views are animated
through their modifiers.
And so to understand how to animate Views,
we're gonna have to take
a time out from animation
and talk about what is a ViewModifier.
Now you've been using ViewModifiers
all over the place so far in Memorize,
aspectRatio, padding,
font, foregroundColor.
All of these things are ViewModifiers.
They modify a View and return a new View
that is a modified version
of View you called them on.
That's what ViewModifiers do.
Now most of these modifiers,
not all, but most of them,
are probably implemented by
just turning right around
and calling a very important
function in View protocol,
added to the View protocol via extension
called modifier.
This function modifier in View,
it takes one argument,
which is essentially
something that implements
the ViewModifier protocol.
So here aspectRatio 2/3
and I've left off the fit
and fill for space reasons,
but aspectRatio 2/3
is likely doing something
like calling on the View,
on the same View that you're
sending your aspectRatio to,
it's saying dot modifier,
AspectModifier, which
is some struct, of 2/3.
So let's talk about what that
ViewModifier protocol is.
By its name you can probably almost guess.
It only has one function in it
and that functions only
job is to take something
and modify it to produce a View.
You could for example, adjust the space
to provide the aspectRatio 2/3,
or ViewModifier could add some
padding around the outside.
That's what the padding
ViewModifier I'm sure does.
So what does this code
look like for protocol?
So here's the protocol ViewModifier.
That first line associatedtype Content.
Again, you guys read your
reading assignment, I hope
and you understand that what
associatedtype Content is
is a don't care for protocols.
Protocols, just like functions and types
they also have don't cares,
but their syntax is
associatedtype Content,
not the angle brackets like
you would see on struct.
So the ViewModifier
protocol has a don't care
called Content.
Doesn't really care what type Content is.
All right, so now once
you understand that,
we can look at the only
function in ViewModifier,
which is body.
Body takes a Content
which is a don't care,
we don't really care what that is,
and it returns very importantly some View.
And inside that body it
just has to take the Content
that was given to it
and somehow make up a View and return it.
Now when you call dot modifier on View,
the Content that's passed
is the View you sent
dot modifier to, right?
The View you called dot modifier on,
that is the content.
That makes it so any ViewModifier
that is called with dot modifier
is going to get the View it's
called on as the Content.
That's why we say it modifies that View.
It's gonna create a new View
using that View you sent
it to as its Content.
Right, so let's see, an example of this,
to make this all more concrete.
Let's say I wanted to have a ViewModifier
that took any View like our Text ghost,
or any View an Image, anything,
and it modified it so that
it looked like a card.
Cardifies it, basically.
That's what we wanna build.
Now that sounds like that's a
pretty complicated modifier.
It's more complicated than
just putting padding around it
or something, perfectly fine though.
It's actually gonna be
quite simple modifier,
but conceptually it makes sense.
Now in our app we wouldn't
necessarily even need a modifier
like this because we only
have one kind of View
that ever gets cardified,
but you could imagine an app
where you have some cards
that have images on them, some have emoji,
some just have text or
something, other flashcards,
but they're all having the same card.
That might make sense to be
able to cardify any View.
Here's what the code would look like.
The first line there is actually
how we would call the modifier.
For example, if we wanted to cardify
our ghost text right there,
we would say dot modifier,
that very important View function
and the argument is a ViewModifier.
Now I'm gonna call my ViewModifier,
you can see struct Cardify
there in the next line.
I'm gonna call it Cardify and
it actually takes an argument.
We'll talk about that.
But eventually though, I
actually want this to say
Text goes dot Cardify,
just like I say dot
foregroundColor, dot padding,
I wanna say dot Cardify.
I don't wanna have to
say dot modifier Cardify.
So on the next slide
we're gonna show how we get
from dot modifier Cardify
to dot Cardify.
But for now, let's focus on
how we would implement
this Cardify ViewModifier
'cause this has to be something
that takes the Text ghost
and modifies it, turns it into a new View
that looks like a card.
That's what this thing's gonna do.
First thing I wanna look at
here is the Content argument
to that body function in ViewModifier.
I made it yellow here all
the places it appears,
it's the argument to body.
You can see up top the Text
ghost is what that Content is
and then also look down inside the ZStack
I'm embedding that Content, it's a View
and I'm embedding it inside my ZStack
in the same place I would've
put that back in my old code.
So now it's gonna take any
View and embed it right there
in my ZStack on the face of the card.
So do you see how this is
going to modify the View
that you send it to to look like a card.
Now, one thing to note
here that's interesting is
this ViewModifier needs some information,
needs to know whether the
card is face up or face down.
It's a struct so I just
add a var isFaceUp to it
and we know that if you have a
var and it's not initialized,
then whoever creates this struct,
which is up there in the top line,
it needs to specify the value of it.
So hopefully this is looking
from kind of familiar to you
when you do these modifiers,
obviously a lot of them take arguments
foregroundColor takes a Color
and padding can take things
like the top or bottom
and how many points to pad
and all these other arguments.
Those are just gonna be inside
the ViewModifier for padding,
for example.
So dot modifier, that
function, it returns a View,
returns something that conforms to View
that is going use this purple
contents of body right here
to draw the View.
Now modifier doesn't directly
return this purple code
returns something else that's also a View,
but that's something else
is going to use this purple
code to draw what it draws.
And simple as that.
Dot modifier is just going to
use this ViewModifier thing,
pass the View that it
is sent to to the body,
it's gonna get whatever built
into whatever's necessary
and returned as the new View to use.
And then of course since
that thing is a View,
we can send another modifier to it
and another modifier to that, et cetera
and Swift is very smart
about keeping track
when it's modifications,
modifications, modifications
so that it can do things like animation.
So how do we get from this
text dot modifier syntax
to dot Cardify,
'cause really that's
why we want dot Cardify.
Really easy, you actually
know how to do this.
I'm gonna create an extension
to the View protocol,
add the function cardify
that cardify obviously returns some View
and it's just gonna
return self dot modifier
of the Cardify.
Remember this is an extension to View,
so self is the View.
So of course I can call
dot modifier on self
and pass it the right ViewModifier,
in this case, our Cardify.
All right, so let's go implement this
in our Memorize application.
Our goal in this demo is to
make it so that any View,
including our ghost and
Pac-Man here can be cardified.
That means putting this border
around it when it's face up
or just drawing this
back when it's face down.
Let's start this demo by just imagining
what our code would look like
if we had this cardifier.
Let's make some space here so
we can see what's going on.
I'm gonna take the part
of our card right now
that's gonna get cardified,
which is just the Pie and the Text.
We're gonna separate
them out from the code
that actually is doing the cardification.
Then we're gonna take this ZStack
that has the stuff we want in it,
and I'm gonna cardify it
by saying dot cardify.
Of course the cardifier needs to know
whether this thing is face up or not.
So I'm gonna pass that is face up in there
and we're gonna see how this
is going to be specified
in a bit.
Now this code, that's the thing
that actually does the
cardification, right?
Puts the RoundedRectangles
in the back or in the front.
Just gonna cut that out of here
and I'm gonna go put that
in my Cardify ViewModifier.
Before I go over there,
I eventually do want this to say this,
but we know that really the ViewModifiers
are calling this View
function called modifier
then you just specify the
ViewModifier you want.
So the ViewModifier we're
gonna create to do this,
I'm gonna call it Cardify
and it's of course going to
have to take that face up
as an argument.
So this is what this cardifier
right here is really gonna do
and this is gonna end up being
a function we're gonna create
that it's just one line that calls this.
So we'll comment this
out and we'll put it back
once we add this one
liner that calls this.
But this is what this is going to do
and of course it says
unresolved identifier Cardify,
we have to go write the code
that does this ViewModifier.
So let's hop over and do that.
File, New File.
This is not a SwiftUI
View, it's a ViewModifier.
So we'll click this, we'll go here,
I'm gonna call this Cardify,
that's the name of my new modifier.
Notice it's not putting
it in the right place.
It's a good example of seeing that.
I don't want it in this
blue thing at the top.
I want this down here,
and this yellow folder
and I want this to be the same place
that this yellow folder is up here.
So hopefully you all are
remembering to do that
so you're not ending up with
files all over the place
they shouldn't be.
So create Cardify.
Here is Cardify.
Now of course ViewModifiers
are very much a UI thing,
so we don't say import
Foundation right there,
and creating a ViewModifier, very simple.
Struct Cardify, it's a ViewModifier
and when we do this we're
immediately gonna get an error
that says Cardify does not
conform to protocol ViewModifier.
This protocol only has one function in it,
it's called body and it takes
content as the argument.
This Content right here is
a don't care that we get
from this protocol.
So protocols can have don't cares too.
They specify them with
that associatedtype syntax
that you read about in
your reading homework
and so this can be anything.
This is a don't care.
We'll talk about what it's
gonna be in just a second.
Then of course this is a ViewModifier,
it's modifying a View and
then returning some new View
that is the modified version of this.
So this argument right here,
just to remind you from the slides
when we call back here, modifier Cardify,
the content that we're
being asked to modify
is going to be whatever
View we call modifier on.
So we're gonna be calling
modifier on the ZStack.
So inside our cardifier in this case
the content will be that ZStack.
This is always the View that
you're calling dot modifier on.
So what goes in here?
Well in here we just have
to create the modified View,
in other words, a cardified View.
So I'm just gonna paste
that thing we had before
and of course this still
has to be in a ZStack
because we still have
these RoundedRectangles
stacked on top of each other.
So let's go ahead and do that.
And we have some things undefined in here,
like cornerRadius and edgeLineWidth.
Those are over here,
that's drawing constants.
We don't need them over here anymore
since we're using
cardification to do our card.
So we'll just pop those over here.
That fixes most of our problem.
We do know that we have
to pass this is space up
as an argument here
and Cardify needs to
know whether it's face up
so it's gonna have a var
isFaceUp which is a bool
and I'm not gonna set
it equal to something
so anytime someone creates
a Cardify like here,
they have to tell me what
the value of this isFaceUp is
And then I'm gonna use
this isFaceUp inside
anytime I wanna check
and see if I'm face up.
Now what about this isMatched thing.
Well isMatched really does
not belong in Cardify.
Matching has to do with our card game.
This Cardify can Cardify any View,
not just Views in our card game.
This could put a card face
up, face down on any View.
so we wanna keep this generic.
We don't want it to be tied
to the rest of our app.
This is a nice reusable thing
we could actually use another game--
Let's say we wrote some other game
that had some Texts on
cards and Images on cards
and emoji on cards all
mixed in the same app.
Well, we can use Cardify to
Cardify any of those things.
But we couldn't really
have the matching in there
because matching is specific
to this app, Memorize.
And then the last thing we wanna do here
is obviously this Content
needs to be somewhere in here.
Well I'm gonna put it
exactly where it was before.
Just to put content.
Content is the View, the ZStack
that modifier is being sent to here.
So I'm just gonna take this,
it's going to pop right in here.
Now I've done it.
This is a ViewModifier
that takes this Content,
any View that dot modifier sent here
and it puts it in a ZStack
with the RoundedRectangles
or if it's faced up, it
does this, et cetera.
This is something that
cardifies this content.
What did, let's go back here.
Let's go ahead and run, see if this works.
It looks like the backs
of cards are working.
Let's try the front.
Ooh, this is working nicely.
Now there is one problem here
which is that if I get a match
and then I click on another
card, oh these don't go away.
That's 'cause I took that
matching stuff out of there.
So we've gotta fix that.
And the other thing we gotta fix is
we want this nicer syntax dot cardify.
So let's fix this nicer syntax first
and then we'll fix the
problem where matched cards
are are still being included here
when they should be taken away.
This function that does cardify
is just something we're gonna
add to View with an extension.
And it really makes the
most sense obviously
to put it in this file
'cause this is where the
Cardify ViewModifier is.
So this is the place we would
wanna put an extension to View
that has the func cardify.
Now cardify is also going to have to take
whether it's face up as an argument
and it's just gonna return
that cardified View,
really easy to implement.
Just gonna call self,
self is a View, we're an
extension to View here,
modifier, we're gonna give it a Cardify
with isFaceUp being this
isFaceUp that's passed to us.
And that's it.
Simple as pie.
No pun intended.
We have made cardify here
into a nice little function
that we can call on any
View just like this.
You don't need this slightly
more bulky way of doing it
and this should feel to you just like font
of some dot largeTitle,
foregroundColor Color.
What about the fact that matched
cards are not disappearing?
I'm just gonna do that by
only doing this whole card
if the card is face up or
the card is not yet matched.
The card is faced up or
I haven't matched it yet,
then boom, I'm going to
put that card up there.
Otherwise I just want blank space,
which is exactly what we had before.
Now this is giving an error here that says
function declares an opaque
return type, yep, some View,
but has no return return statements.
Oh, that's right.
There's no return statement in here.
I guess I could say
return that fixes that,
but what about in the
else case of this if.
We have this if no else,
we're not returning anything in that case.
So that's no good and I'm gonna fix this
in a kind of novel interesting way,
which is I'm just gonna make
this into a ViewBuilder.
If I turn this function
into a ViewBuilder,
then this gets now interpreted
as a list of Views.
Yes with ifs to decide whether
certain Views are in or out,
but this is a list of Views.
It's either gonna end up
being the ZStack, the View,
or it's gonna be EmptyView
if this is not true.
Look no errors, simple as that.
We've got our ViewBuilder.
Run it over here, let's try and see.
This is working.
Let's make a match and
oh, it took 'em away
'cause this if was not
true and they're gone.
Now one other thing we can do
and just make sure that our
cardify is really working,
instead of doing this ZStack,
let's try some other Views.
How about like a Circle
and let's go ahead and bring
back our canvas over here.
We can see this in action.
Yep, look at that.
It's a Circle put on a card.
We can even do Circle
with a little bit of padding on it, right?
Or maybe we'll put a Capsule in here.
That's another built in Shape Capsule.
That's what Capsule Shapes
look like if you're wondering.
We could put maybe something like Text.
Hello world, look at that, cardified that.
So cardify is a general
cardifier, ViewModifier
that we built that can modify any View.
All right, this is good
that we have done all
this ViewModifier stuff
because the next lecture we're
gonna talk about animation,
and when it comes to animating Views,
not shapes like this Pie, but
animating Views themselves,
it's all about ViewModifiers.
They were really only
animating ViewModifiers,
we don't actually
animate Views themselves.
We'll be looking into that next lecture
and seeing how we can animate this card.
Cards have a lot of
animation that they want.
They want to flip over, for example.
That's a nice animation that a card wants,
so it's really good that
we've put this cardification
to a ViewModifier so that
we can animate it next time.
That is it for today.
I will talk to you then.
- [Narrator] For more, please
visit us @stanford.edu.